Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com
Episode 87
Osman Bey!
Brother, call for help! Now!
Allah!
My Sheik!
Close Söğüt!
Don't let anyone in or out!
No one will leave!
No one!
Get everyone who came to and left the
tavern!
Don't ever return without a trace!
Come on!
Yes, my Bey!
Konur, come on!
Brothers, come on!
Come on!
I hope everyone is fine, Cornelia.
Someone obviously wants to kill Osman Bey.
How could they explode all Söğüt just
for Osman Bey?
Who would do this cruel act, Cornelia?
Of course...
...at such a time...
...there can be no one other than Gündüz
Bey who wants to kill Osman Bey.
What are you saying...
...Selvi Hatun?
Don't you know, Erdoğdu?
Söğüt exploded!
I will go inform Malhun.
People say Gündüz Bey exploded Söğüt.
What are you saying, Cornelia?
How could Gündüz Bey become such an
evil man?
Didn't we know him at all?
Don't, Cornelia.
Gündüz Bey is a prisoner.
How could he do all this?
Someone is trapping my bey.
Don't you see?
It doesn't matter if I see or not.
Everyone is talking about it.
If Gündüz Bey can't justify himself...
...he will die.
How can my Bey justify himself while he
is prisoned?
But if he runs away...
...he can save himself.
-Akça!
-I am fine.
-Are you?
-I am.
I am fine, my Bey.
Father!
My Sheik!
Help!
Come on!
My Sheik!
Father!
They are still together.
But it won't be long.
Weak!
Both his breath and his heartbeat!
My Allah, protect him!
My Sheik!
-Stretcher!
Come on, give me the stretcher!
Come on!
Be careful!
Slowly! Be careful!
It is all because of me!
It is all because of me, my Bey!
What did you do?
These are the irons we put in gunpowder,
my Bey!
My Sheik!
They hit us with our ammunition!
Take some alps with you, go to your tent!
Those who did this to us...
...may trap you there as well.
Come on!
I hope I will come across those who
did this, my Bey!
Don't cry, my Ayşe.
No one shows us mercy.
Why are you crying?
Mari is gone, my Bey.
With her baby.
I can't bare it.
My Bey!
My Bey, someone exploded...
...Söğüt, the tavern.
What are you saying, Erdoğdu?
Osman?
Alps?
Tell me!
There are many martyrs, my Bey.
But the people are already talking
about you, my Bey.
they say, Gündüz Bey exploded Söğüt...
...and tried to kill Osman Bey.
We need to run away.
If a leaf falls from the tree, they will
say it is me!
Who did this, Ayşe?
I don't know, Gündüz.
But someone is trying to blame us.
What will we do now?
We will run away.
We will run away and then justify
ourselves.
As long as we stay in this hole, we
can't figure out who did it.
Erdoğdu, you know what to do.
I already got the carriage ready,
my Bey.
We have to go before the guardian Alps
come.
It is not the right time but...
How can we leave the tribe in the open?
Get him up!
Come on! Go! Go! Go!
Come on!
My Sheik!
-Come on!
Come on!
Rest of you, go help people!
Hang on, my Sheik!
Hang on!
Come on!
Hang on, my Sheik!
Hang on!
My Bey!
My Bey! My Bey!
We found the car on the other
street...
...which brought the apples.
But no one is there.
Help!
Take my Sheik!
I will spoil that devil's game!
Come on!
Come on! Help!
Trap!
Vile dog!
The devil's dog!
Their games don't end!
I will make him talk!
Bring him, come on!
Yes, My Bey!
Up! Up!
Come on!
Walk!
What are you carrying, brother Erdoğdu?
I'm taking supplies to the surrounding
villages, brother.
Osman Bey's order.
He wants me to complete Gündüz Bey's
duties.
Go!
Selvi Hatun!
Selvi Hatun...
...I saw something but I don't know
to whom or how to tell.
What is it, Cornelia?
Tell me.
Tell me, Cornelia.
What did you see?
Gündüz Bey...
...and Ayşe Hatun are running away.
What are you saying, Cornelia?
How can they?
I saw them getting into the barrels.
Erdoğdu is taking them.
Erdoğdu!
Do you know where they went?
I do.
Run! Run!
Help me!
Are you afraid?
You should've been.
Hang on, my Sheik! Hang on!
Hang on, my Sheik!
In the name of Allah!
Hang on!
Father!
Father! What happened?
What happened, Kumral Abdal?
How is he?
Allah will heal I hope but...
...his wounds are too deep.
He lost so much blood.
We will bandage his wounds and wait.
Hang on, father! Hang on!
Don't leave us in the dark!
Hang on!
We couldn't protect our Sheik, Bala Hatun.
We are sorry.
If my Sheik opened his eyes now...
...he would tell us to
consent to the calamity.
He would say that every cloud
has a silver lining.
Allah knows but we don't.
How can our hearts find healing now?
Father!
Give me a bandage, Kumral Abdal!
Give me a bandage!
My Sheik!
Bala...
What will we do if something
happens to him?
No. No.
My Sheik is strong!
He will survive!
Kumral Abdal!
I hope so, my Bey.
I hope so.
Where do we go now, my Bey?
You hide the carriage.
There are caves nearby.
We will spend the night there.
All right, my Bey.
Gündüz...
...how will we justify ourselves?
We will find those who betrayed us,
my Ayşe.
Don't worry.
My Bey!
Someone is coming, my Bey!
Ayşe!
Ayşe, run! Come on!
Where are you running to, Gündüz Bey?
Come on, Ayşe!
Let's get them!
Why didn't you stay with Bala Hatun?
There are many men there. Don't
worry, Cerkutay.
Alps!
Be careful.
They destroyed it.
Who would do this, Cerkutay?
Why?
I don't know.
But we will find out.
It can be fixed.
There is no need to worry.
Alps!
Prepare a strecther.
Let's take our brothers.
Yes, my Bey.
The paintings.
They are entrusted.
We have to take them.
We need them.
Aygül!
Çoban!
It's a trap!
No! No!
Aygül!
Aygül! Aygül! No! Aygül!
No!
Aygül!
Aygül look at me!
Open your eyes!
Aygül!
You are fine!
Are you all right?
I am fine.
I am fine. I am fine.
It is all right.
It is all right now.
Çoban!
Çoban, Cerkutay!
Çoban! Çoban!
Get back! Get back! Çoban!
Brother! Çoban!
Çoban!
Çoban! Çoban! Çoban!
My brother!
We did this so that it would explode
in the chest of the infidel.
This is fate.
We were shot with our own.
You are not going anywhere, brother!
Where are you going before we fight
the infidel?
That is what I am saying, brother
Cerkutay.
The conquests will be done
without me but...
...my heart is relieved.
The conquests will be made.
Brother...
...tell me Bey, brother.
Tell him to bless his right to me.
Brother...
...a Turk can't be prisoned...
...before he dies.
I bear witness that there is no god
but Allah...
...and I bear witness that Muhammad
is the servant and Messenger of Allah.
No!
No! No! No! No! No!
He is gone! He is gone Cerkutay!
Come on, Çoban! Come on!
Come on!
Osman will be torn into pieces...
...just like his alps.
We are just starting, Barkın.
Osman didn't die but...
...he will watch the destruction of his
reputation and loved ones.
We took everyone he trusted with us
but...
...Turgut and Kosses...
...they still showed up.
It means we're not attacking hard enough,
Barkın.
You will not stop until their swords are
against each other.
There will not be a single place
they have not been hit.
Those who were asleep woke up.
And burned them with the ammunition
they thought they would conquer.
It will explode the moment someone
walks in.
You are like a snake among them, Cornelia.
No, I am just a poor loyal woman.
They took Mari here as well.
What you've learned from Mari will
be useful.
Thanks to you, we will shoot Osman
with his own arm.
But no one will ever suspect me.
What harm could a woman mourning for her
lady do?
You will be too harmful, Cornelia.
Too harmful.
While we explode Söğüt...
...you will play a game to Gündüz.
If you succeed, everyone will believe that
Gunduz burned Söğüt to escape.
It will be so easy.
I am not only destroying his people but
I am destroying everything.
Cornelia must be finished now.
Oh my dear Cornelia.
There is nothing she can't do.
What if Osman forgives Gündüz?
Osman can't take all the pressure and
forgive Gündüz.
He will kill him.
Then we reveal the innocence of Gündüz
and...
...burn Osman's heart.
Will he kill him?
If he doesn't...
...neither Kosses nor Turgut won't forgive
him.
In this case, they will kill Gündüz.
Barkın...
...those who don't attend the war win it.
We are not the ones who are fighting...
...but the ones who are starting the war.
Darkness always wins.
Give this poison to Cornelia.
A poison that even the most skilled
healer cannot understand.
Odorless.
Invisible.
We will hasten the fading of that
weak light of Oğuz.
Söğüt will surrender to a dark fear.
Who did this?
We had enemies from inside.
We beheaded all of them.
We had enemies from outside.
We crashed them with our swords.
But...
...but this...
...is a devil hiding in the darkness!
We will be on alert.
That devil can hide.
I will speak the language he understands.
There is nowhere else to go, Gündüz Bey.
We will return to the tribe.
You can't escape justice!
Selvi Hatun, we are running for justice!
We are running to justify ourselves.
Don't push it, Gündüz Bey!
If that so...
...you gave me no other choice.
Hatun!
Will you kill me too, Ayşe Hatun?
Run, my Bey!
Ayşe!
Come on!
Söğüt
There is no trace.
Alps searched everywhere.
Whoever did the explosion is someone who
knows Söğüt well.
I don't want to say it but...
...it is someone among us.
I don't know, Osman Bey.
Once a traitor always a traitor.
Tell me, does anyone know Söğüt better
than Gündüz?
This is such a huge game that...
...only the devil can pull it off.
I don't know who the enemy is.
But I know his cruelty well.
My brother is not cruel.
Of course, he made mistakes...
...but...
He would never do such a vile thing.
He would never harm our people and home
like this.
There is evidence, Osman Bey.
Who killed my family is Gündüz.
Can we come in, my Bey?
Come in!
In the name of Allah.
Tell me.
My Bey...
...Akça.
What happened to Akça?
It was a trap.
They set a trap in the tent, my Bey.
Akça Çoban...
...is martyred.
What are you saying?
Akça!
Başsungur.
They killed the guardian alps too, my Bey.
They destroyed everything on their way.
They also burned the catapults.
Akça!
"Verily we belong to Allah and verily
to him do we return."
This is such an enemy that...
...he doesn't even have a shadow.
He clearly hides in the dark.
But I will find him.
I will find him.
Tell us as well, Osman Bey.
How?
I have a prisoner from those who attacked
the tavern.
I'll make him talk and learn the truth.
Can I come in, my Bey?
Come in!
In the name of Allah.
Osman Bey...
...the rascal tried to escape.
He tried to kill me.
I had to kill him.
What are you saying?
How do you do that without asking me?
My Bey! My Bey!
He tried to kill us.
He injured Barkın Bey as well.
We searched the whole Söğüt but couldn't
find anyone.
I swear that I will burn these devils
alive who burned my heart...
...to the ground!
They should fear my rage!
It is great that the Söğüt burned down,
Argus.
Also they blame Gündüz for all of this.
Good.
Both Kosses and Turgut can't trust Osman
anymore.
What about Gündüz?
He is a dead man now.
We can say that.
What will we gain from all this, sir?
Both Kosses and Turgut will grow apart
from Osman.
Someone wants to leave Osman alone.
But who?
Who is this secret ally of us?
Who?
Sir, I was told to convey this to you.
You!
Of course, you!
No one could make such a great move
but you.
Who could?
All right.
Father, come on.
Open your eyes.
Allah is the healer.
Allah is the healer, Bala Hatun.
Hang on, my Sheik, hang on!
There is always hope, Bala Hatun.
We will pray.
Thank you.
Father!
Allah...
...may you give healing to my Sheik.
Father!
He is burning!
Do something, Kumral Abdal!
I hope this will work.
In the name of Allah.
Allah is the healer.
My Sheik.
Akça Dervish...
...the service must continue at the lodge.
Thank you, İbrahim Fakih.
Tell me whatever is missing in the lodge.
It is a blessing to me to serve the
household where Allah is remembered...
...and where Allah's friends are.
Of course, we will.
May Allah be pleased with you.
There is not much needed to serve
the lodge.
There isn't anyone.
They lost our track.
We are fighting our family.
What do we do, Gündüz?
We will get rid of the slanders, my Ayşe.
Everything will be fine.
We are innocent.
The truth will come out.
Eventually.
What if we die like this?
Then...
...what will happen to our son?
I wish I could see my son one more time.
I wish I could, Gündüz.
My Ayşe.
Allah is not with those who give up...
...he is with those who are patient.
We will be patient.
Erdoğdu?
Ayşe! Ayşe! Ayşe!
This is the end, Gündüz Bey!
Amen.
Bala...
My Bala!
My Bala.
The good and evil is from Allah.
We will bear it.
We know that...
...none of us is eternal in this world.
It hurts so bad, my Osman!
So bad!
Everything is for us, my Bala.
Everything is for us.
Don't lose hope.
But...
...we must be prepared for anything.
Allah is the one who gives and takes.
We will heal.
We will be patient.
We will be strong.
You are a strong Hatun.
You will get through this.
You will be patient.
Söğüt is filled with snakes, Kosses.
They don't leave a trace.
You can't feel their breath.
But it poisons everywhere.
Everything happened after the Vizier died
and Geyhatu left.
Do you think the Sultan is involved in
this?
Would he get involved in such a thing...
...to damage Osman's power? If that
is the case...
...Gündüz is the best pawn for this job.
I don't think it is the Sultan.
This is a new devil.
That Gündüz will be justified for sure.
He was just about to be put on a trial
but these happened.
He worked with that traitor Vezir before
as well.
It seems Gündüz Bey got skillful
in this area.
Right.
You are slouching Samuel.
This is bad news.
Gündüz Bey ran away.
What do you mean he ran away?
Ah, Osman Bey, ah!
This is what happens when you don't do
justice in time.
Gündüz burnt the tavern and killed many
innocent people. He won't stop after all.
I've waited Kosses.
I've waited so he gets fairly judged.
I've waited so he gets the appropriate
sentence.
But he chose to escape.
Oh, Gündüz.
Now that you ran away...
...you will be killed by me even if you go
to hell.
Don't worry, we will find him.
Send news to everywhere, Samuel.
I will drown the one who brings him to me
alive or dead in gold.
-Now, go!
-Yes, Sir.
Ah, Osman Bey!
Ah!
Alps!
We buried our martyrs.
Those dogs attacked us...
...in a way that suits them.
Their intention is to bow our heads.
But...
...we won't let them enjoy.
Those who face us don't live long.
They hide their daggers.
They attack from the shadows.
We will lighten them up out of the
darkness they are in with our faith.
We'll bring their end with
the sword of justice!
Allahu Akbar!
Come on.
Osman Bey.
Your heart is even bigger than what
I've heard, Osman Bey.
Your faith is even stronger than
what I've heard.
I've learned from my father Ertuğrul Ghazi
and Sheik Edebali.
Thank you.
But...
whenever I face a difficult conflict...
I always went to Sheik Edebali.
But now he is in death's bed.
Death comes from Allah, Osman Bey.
Edebali is the light of the Oghuzs.
You've been enlightened by
him all this time.
You will find a way out.
Söğüt on one side..
Kayı on the other...
They want to involve my brother
into this.
When Söğüt is struggling
with death...
now my brother is a part
of the problem.
This creates a greater problem.
It'll be solved eventually, but...
What does Allah say in the verse?
''O' believers!
Keep justice for Allah.
Be people who testify for justice.
Don't let your grudges take you astray.
Be just. This is most appropriate.
Be afraid of Allah.
Without a doubt, Allah knows
what you do.''
I heard that, your brother,
Gündüz Bey...
made such mistakes before too.
And you forgave him, Osman Bey.
The evidence is clear. An innocent's
blood shouldn't be on you.
You are the bey.
You should make your decision soon.
It's your verdict.
If the justice is late, it's not just.
Justice will be served.
Many innocent people faded away
in Söğüt.
Why is Osman Bey facing this?
You are right.
Your brother kills the wife of
your commander. What is this?
Beys.
The rest is gossip.
Don't eat a Muslim's flesh.
Not every finger on a hand
is the same.
It's apparent. Gündüz Bey is
not like Osman Bey.
Osman Bey carries the sword of
justice.
He'll kill Gündüz and his wife.
We say the same.
He will, surely.
But...
let's say we are wrong,
Osman Bey can't rule justly...
then...
as the Kızılbeyoğlu beys,
we'll take our position.
He works with lords, rebels.
He can't protect anyone.
I don't believe that he can secure
the justice. He cdo it sooner.
This way or another.
Everything will be revealed.
Nothing will be left in the dark.
Son.
We did it, mother.
We buried our martyrs.
Now...
Traitor!
Traitors!
With Erdoğdu's help, they escaped
in barrels, Osman Bey.
We caught them in the
cave before too late.
Traitors!
Boran. Cerkutay.
Bring him.
My bey.
Why did you run, brother?
Why?
Take my brother to the caged tent.
As you order, my bey.
Traitor!
Thank you.
You saved Gündüz Bey from
a great mistake.
My Allah. Protect my children
and the unity of the tribe.
You've done a great job, Cornelia.
Will you say something, Barkın Bey?
I don't have much time.
For Selcan.
Don't worry. Her time will come too.
But this is for the never-ending
light of the Oghuz.
Kumral Abdal creates medicines
to heal Edebali.
We must stop it.
Edebali shouldn't wake up, Cornelia.
I'll kill that light with my own hands.
Osman.
Osman Bey.
We didn't do anything.
My brother wouldn't kill
an innocent baby.
Why did you run away?
I heard it. They attacked Söğüt.
They see me responsible for that too?
Why did you run?
Don't you trust my justice?
Not at all. They want to put
everything on me, Osman!
Did I have any other choice
to clean my name?
They want to put in on us, not you.
They want to break us.
Don't you know that running away
makes you guilty?
Why didn't you think?
I didn't feel like dying before finding
who did all this, brother.
I'll find that traitor.
You believe me. Dying is not a
problem now.
You will die, brother.
I didn't believe you.
I'm searching for the truth.
And the truth will be revealed
when you die.
Those who serve an ancient goal...
are like a tree that's roots go
to the center of the world.
And time is a horrific storm.
It bends that tree but it can't
take it off.
You didn't forget it.
That's why I'm alive.
Master Darius.
I can't believe my eyes.
Time didn't even touch you.
Nikola. Nikola. My naughtiest student.
Still apple?
It symbolizes Adam's sin.
And reminds me of my sins.
Master Darius, forgive my curiosity.
Why now?
While I was fighting this difficult
war with stupid treacherous...
lords and a fool emperor...
while these barbarians were invading
our lands, why was I alone?
Why now?
I didn't think you would struggle this
much to destroy a little Turkish bey.
You disappointed me.
But don't worry.
I'm here now.
In Osman's heart.
Gündüz Bey and Ayşe Hatun.
are accused of Turgut Bey's wife,
Michael Kosses' sister...
and our guest...
Mari's murder.
I was forgiven when I went astray
from the right path.
Now, I'm being trialed with a slander.
I don't even have a single
word to say.
My bey, we did nothing.
Why are you still letting
them talk, Osman Bey?
Why are you letting them
pierce my heart further?
Turgut Bey.
Boran. Bring the evidence.
Say it. Did this bowl come
out of your tent.
It belongs to us, my bey.
And you...
can you swear that you took this
bowl from Ayşe Hatun, Cornelia?
I wish my hands were broken so that
I couldn't take it.
Ayşe Hatun gave it to me with
her own hands.
I took it.
The flask that poisoned my sister
was in their tent.
What are you still questioning,
Osman Bey?
The truth, Kosses.
The truth.
She kidnapped my wife
with the vizier first.
Now, he killed her for who knows
whom, Osman Bey!
This is the truth.
You keep saying the same thing, Turgut!
Gündüz!
And you, Kosses?
Who did I give Mari to?
I gave Mari to you, for the security
of my tribe.
It's you who gave her to Nikola.
Shut up, Gündüz Bey.
Don't try to cover your guilt
with my faults.
You will die today.
Only I can decide that, Kosses!
Be decent.
When your turn comes...
you will speak.
-Saltuk.
-My bey.
Come on.
With a slander, you took Gündüz
apart from Osman.
Genious!
Kosses, Turgut, they will fall apart.
What else does he have?
We got what he has.
But he has outer support, Nikola.
I heard that Umur died.
Osman buried Umur with his own hands.
Ivaz is next.
I'll kill him.
Osman will take caution.
He won't make the same mistake.
While you kill him...
I'll take Kosses to my side.
No. No.
Osman might be after something.
We'll be careful.
You won't contact until you are sure
that Kosses and Turgut aren't with him.
So, master...
what do you want from me?
You were unseated.
You were insulted.
Did your grudge take it's
direction to Turgut Bey who replaced you?
We aren't nailed to these seats,
Osman Bey.
We paid the price of our mistake.
I have no grudge nor greed.
Especially against a woman.
Especially against a woman who
carries a child.
Don't speak my sister's name!
Whatever the verdict is...
I will kill you, Gündüz!
Kosses!
Let me go!
It's your sister!
But she died in my tribe.
And it's my brother who is
accused.
The verdict is mine to give.
Either sit or leave!
I'm silent for now...
Osman Bey.
If your verdict isn't just...
then, I'll serve the justice
with my sword.
If you don't get convinced
of my justice...
you can use your sword.
But know that...
I won't hold back.
Alright.
Gündüz Bey.
You giving Mari out earlier,
shows an example.
Your anger against Turgut Bey and Kosses,
shows a reason.
The poison being found in your tent,
shows evidence.
And running away...
is accepting your crime.
Gündüz Bey.
If it's a slander, you will speak.
You can't bow down to slander.
Speak now.
Come, my girl.
Come, sit.
-Did you do what I said?
-Yes, Mother Selcan.
May it heal our sheik.
Go and bring a bowl.
I'll prepare the herbs.
Alright.
Is this for Sheik Edebali, Mother Selcan?
Yes, my girl.
I boiled bone broth.
After adding the herbs...
our sheik will be on his feet soon.
I'll do it, Zehra.
Help Mother Selcan.
A little more.
Like this.
Is it good now?
Bring it, my girl.
Bring it here.
Take it there before
it gets cold.
I should go. Maybe they'll
need help.
Go, my girl.
I stepped back from my mistake,
Osman Bey.
A Muslim can't be bit from the
same spot twice.
And about this matter...
I'm not involved with anything.
But it seems that the one who set
the trap thought of everything.
Has anyone seen Gündüz Bey with
poison on his hand?
Has anyone seen Ayşe Hatun putting
poison to the food?
But they were seen
running away from the tribe.
If I hadn't caught them...
Gündüz Bey would be with his
allies now.
Why would an innocent man run,
Osman Bey?
Have you ever been slandered?
Tell me.
May Allah give it to no one.
The one who wants to clean his
name would run.
The one who doesn't want to die with
a stain would run.
The one who doesn't trust the justice
of his brother...
would run.
Forgive me, my bey. But it was me
who led him to escape.
If there is a fault, it's mine.
There are evidence to prove
Gündüz Bey and Ayşe Hatun are guilty.
But no one has seen it.
It's the bey's verdict.
Gündüz Bey and Ayşe Hatun will
be banished.
Osman Bey.
This isn't right, Osman Bey.
This isn't.
Your tribe has no justice!
Shame on you.
People! Osman Bey banished
Gündüz Bey.
Do you hear it, Osman?
You hear it.
Lord Kosses.
Don't act with fury.
This isn't right.
Osman wasn't just.
It's not easy.
It's his brother.
Osman Bey can't kill Gündüz Bey.
He made...
many mistakes...
but he forgave him.
I knew this would happen.
And the dead is my sister.
With a baby on her belly.
Osman owes me two lives, not one.
You are right, Kosses.
It's great pain.
You are right to do anything.
I swear, Mari.
I'll take our revenge.
I swear.
Giros. Samuel.
We are leaving.
Osman.
This destroyed the people's trust
for you.
You hanged yourself.
Come on.
We want justice!
Söğüt
What is it, sisters?
Why are you here?
Mother Selcan prepared soup for my sheik.
We brought it.
May it heal my sheik.
Thank you, sisters.
Proceed.
No need to make it
crowded in here.
One person is enough.
We aren't of the same faith.
But let me get his prayers.
Go on.
God damn you!
Traitors!
Answer for your crimes!
We want justice!
Traitors!
It can't go unpunished.
-Boran.
-My bey.
Alps should get Gündüz Bey
on the road.
They'll company him until
a safe place.
As you order, my bey.
Traitors!
We want justice!
Justice!
Answer for your crime!
We want justice!
Alps.
Return to the tribe.
We'll settle in a inn and rest.
Valiants. The tribe is under
your protection.
Come on.
What will we do, Gündüz?
Where will we go?
Wait.
What is it, Gündüz Bey?
Where are you going this
freely?
Kosses.
Let Ayşe go.
Settle it with me.
No.
You didn't settle it with me.
Your wife poisoned my
sister with her own hands.
My sister and the baby
in her belly.
You owe me two lives, Gündüz Bey.
Neither she nor I did
nothing to anyone!
But if you'll feel relieved...
come at me.
I won't die without fighting.
Ayşe.
Protect yourself.
Look for an opportunity.
Come on.
Come, Kosses.
I will.
Gündüz!
Insolent!
Ayşe...
Make your last prayer, Gündüz Bey.
For my sister.
Gündüz!
With the name of Allah.
Soup will help him, right?
Inshallah, Bala Hatun.
Inshallah.
I can smell it.
Mother Selcan must've put healing
ingredients.
It will heal my sheik, inshallah.
Inshallah.
Allah is healing.
We ask for your help.
May it be good, my Allah.
With the name of Allah.
May it be good, Bala Hatun.
I should take it away.
With the name of Allah.
Allah is healing.
Now is time for duty.
What is it, Osman Bey?
Go to the lord of İğnehisar.
Scare him for good.
He is oppressing people.
He is creating problems
for Turkish merchants.
Tell him that...
if he wants to live
peacefully in his castle...
he'll give the taxes in time.
What if he doesn't?
It will be a conquest, my bey?
They don't expect that for now.
But we'll act when they think
we sleep.
When they expect the least,
we'll ruin their world.
İğnehisar is an important castle.
If we take it...
the gates of İnegöl will be opened.
Great.
Nawruz is here and the conquests
start.
It's time for the Muslims to smile.
May Allah heal our sheik.
Get him on his foot in no time.
Malhun.
Could Gündüz Bey get in Edebali's
blood too?
I'm talking about the explosion
in Söğüt.
No, Selvi.
I don't believe that.
What's there to not believe?
They escaped the tribe at
the time of the explosion.
They drew weapons against me.
Everything is obvious.
Whoever Gündüz Bey is working
with...
they want to kill Osman Bey.
Is it something they haven't done before?
Haven't you told me?
I don't know, Selvi.
I don't know.
Since my father became a martyr...
I'm all mixed up.
Gündüz Bey is two-faced.
He played well.
He worked with the Mongols.
Didn't Mongols kill my uncle?
The one who works with the Mongols...
can do anything, sister.
Do you think all this
happens for nothing?
Mari, Söğüt...
my uncle.
Where does all this point at?
What are you saying, Selvi?
Would Gündüz Bey go this far?
Do you say he killed my
father too?
When he gives out his money,
he thinks justice is served.
Is this your justice?
My bey.
Our scouts.
They found Gündüz Bey's headgear
on the road.
It seems that they were attacked.
Gündüz Bey and Ayşe Hatun.
They were killed.
No!
My children!
What...
They are gone!
May Allah forgive their sins,
Mother Selcan.
Osman.
Osman, why did you send
your brother away?
What did you do, Osman?
Whoever makes a decision
over mine...
will pay the price.
Whoever has done it
did well.
The one who took Gündüz's head...
have made the decision
you couldn't make.
The justice is served now, Osman Bey.
Turgut Bey.
Osman Bey!
Know your place!
I know my place!
You should've known justice.
But no.
You are an enemy to the
one who serves justice.
Tell me it's a lie, Osman Bey.
I stood with you and lost my alps.
I walked on your path...
and lost my wife, child.
Do you know what I have left?
The blood of my loved ones.
Now, take no offense.
My deal is done.
You don't know your words
because of your anger.
Calm your anger first.
Then, we'll have a talk.
Now, leave!
Alps! We are returning
to our tribe.
Our job here is done.
Come on!
Osman Bey.
Let them leave.
Blood can be refreshen.
Me and the Kızılbeyoğulları
are under your command.
We took the road with
people without hearts.
Thank you, Barkın.
Thank you.
Our hearts and arms are of steel.
We are with you.
Did our woods start to burn, Cornelia?
They did indeed, sir.
Kosses and Turgut so firmly
against Osman for releasing Gündüz.
Their unity is shaken to its core.
Good.
Now, it's time to throw bigger
woods on the fire.
What's our next goal, sir?
İhvaz is giving alps to Osman
with many.
He gives him weapons.
We must stop him.
We must get ahead of him.
Osman shouldn't get stronger.
He shouldn't get hopeful.
He shouldn't dream of Kızıl Elma.
Kızıl Elma!
Turks...
become dangerous when they dream.
I won't leave these lands
to the Muslims.
We'll kick them out
of these lands.
We'll take our holy lands back.
These lands will wet with their blood.
I'll bury them alive and
drown them in their blood.
They are gone.
Look at Ertuğrul Bey's son.
His grave is in a mountain.
He's gone...
Everyone is where they belong, sister.
Kosses did the right thing.
Is this how you depart, Gündüz?
Is this how I farewell you?
It's enough, mother.
Who are you weeping for?
They took many lives with them.
Enough, Malhun. My mother is sad.
Stop it!
Mother.
Bala, my girl. He is gone.
My Gündüz is gone.
My Ayşe is gone.
I don't want the bad for you, mother.
It's bad for the tears
you drop.
I know, he wouldn't.
Gündüz wouldn't do this.
They killed my children for nothing.
I'm burning inside.
Malhun Hatun, my mother is right.
I didn't believe any of it.
We are talking about Gündüz Bey
and Ayşe.
After all the things
he has done to us?
It was Gündüz Bey who gave
his neck to Osman Bey.
You don't know what to say
because of your pain.
Don't you see my mother?
Bala, tell me.
Is my sheik alright?
Please say yes.
Kumral Abdal is with him, mother.
Alps.
Shepherd Akça was preparing
ammunition for the war.
They killed him.
Sheik Edebali was illuminating
our way.
They attacked him.
They killed many of our alps.
Umur Bey was coming to aid us.
They killed him too.
Now it's İhvaz Bey.
They'll attack him as they
attacked Umur Bey.
But we'll get on the road...
and take İhvaz Bey.
-Boran.
-My bey.
-Baysungur.
Ready the fastest horses.
Fill your quivers with arrows.
-As you order, my bey.
Barkın.
Come with us.
İhvaz Bey will be happy
to see you.
I couldn't protect my uncle.
I want to protect my father-in-law.
Osman Bey. Gündüz Bey's death
shakened us too.
I want you to know.
You lost a brother.
But you gained one.
Stop, Kosses.
Stop.
What are you doing, Turgut?
First, you took my sister from me.
You couldn't protect her.
Are you here to protect her killer?
I'm not here to protect anyone, Kosses.
I came only with Konur.
To talk with you.
Speak.
Sheathe your sword first, Kosses.
Speak, Turgut.
Osman Bey says that it's a trap.
I believe him for now.
For now.
Tell me, Turgut.
What did Osman Bey tell you that
it convinced you?
Kosses.
Neither the vizier nor Geyhatu...
I've seen many treacherous
plots with my eyes...
whoever planned this plot.
Their aim is to leave Osman Bey alone.
Did they kill my Mari to isolate
Osman Bey?
Think, Kosses.
Gündüz and I are Osman's allies.
We are his comrades. The commanders
of his armies.
And you are his most precious ally.
Don't you see it? They destroyed us all
with a single move.
If Osman knew these...
he should've known that I would
attack Gündüz here.
He knew it. He banished Gündüz
knowingly.
Because now...
Gündüz has to die.
I can die, Turgut.
I can die.
I can do anything for Kayı.
So, who is attacking us, Turgut?
Who?
It must be someone in the darkness.
We have only one chance
to lure them to light.
You and I will be Osman's enemies.
And Gündüz must be dead.
For now, they'll think so.
Tell me, Turgut.
Why should I trust it?
Why should I spare Gündüz's life?
Don't.
Osman Bey wants you to keep
Gündüz Bey and Ayşe Hatun in your castle.
I want that...
if the evidence shows Gündüz's
direction...
you will execute him.
Both of them.
Alright.
You are alive for now.
For now.
Giros. Samuel. Take them.
It's time to expand the
plot at the tribe now.
You have the biggest mission.
We'll get out of these troubles
with new conquests.
-Stay in peace, Turgut Bey.
-Thank you.
May Allah bless your jihad.
From Barkın Bey.
My bey, it's from Kayı Tribe.
Barkın Bey sent it.
My brother, Umur Bey. He was killed
on his way to the Kayı Tribe.
If my father has fallen on this way...
we are on the right path.
Things are complicated at the tribe too.
It's not good.
They are filled with slackness.
Look at the borders, Serhat!
As soon as we came, we smelled
the battle.
My father is a martyr.
Inshallah, we'll be too.
Amin, my bey.
The caravan will continue on Kızılhan
road.
We'll go to Badirbük to
see Barkın.
Let's hear it form him.
My bey, do you know the messenger?
Maybe it's a trap?
If it's a trap, we'll kill
some heathens before reaching Kayı.
We'll tell them that we fought
on our way.
Come on!
The poison flows in Edebali's
veins.
My beautiful Cornelia.
Oghuz's weak light is fading
away forever.
The rest is darkness.
The darkness is ours, sir.
But, if you forgive my curiosity,
I want to ask something.
You can't learn without
asking, Cornelia.
My beautiful child.
Ask away.
This Turk, Barkın.
Why is he always with you?
We have nothing in commong. Even our
faiths are different.
Power-hunger, Cornelia.
Power-hunger makes you the dog
of your enemy.
We hold his leash.
I'll greet İhvaz now.
He must've received my letter.
No. You don't deserve this, sister.
You are right.
Gündüz Bey blinded them.
I can't understand it either.
Gündüz Bey is Osman's brother.
But you see it, Selvi.
Isn't it obvious.
You are right, sister.
But know it...
Bala Hatun tries to win Selcan Hatun's
favor.
No. Bala Hatun doesn't do
such things.
My dear sister.
You think everyone is like you.
But it isn't like that.
When it's about power...
no one knows anyone.
Brothers and sisters fight each other.
But you think that I'm being
sceptical.
Your beautiful heart knows the best.
Harmankaya Castle
Osman loves you so much, Gündüz Bey.
I never should've let my sister
join you.
I never should I let her leave
her safe castle to go to your tents.
Even if it's not by your hands...
she died because of you.
Spit, Kosses.
Spit your hatred through the slander.
Hatred?
Don't, Gündüz Bey.
If my sister hadn't die...
I almost loved you.
Sir, Lord Nikola is here.
You are already dead.
Don't let me hear anything.
Meanwhile, we'll see...
if Nikola is involved or not.
Sit.
Are you any better?
Kosses.
Did you really kill Kosses?
You didn't really ask me this
question, Nikola.
What was I supposed to do?
Let the murderer of my sister
live?
And Osman? What will he say
about this.
What will he say?
We both lost our siblings.
What can he say?
It's over. You are still friends
with Osman, then?
Don't be ridiculous, Nikola.
What friendship? Do you think
such a thing is still possible?
Osman was about to march my castle.
He lost his friends.
He lost his brother.
All his moves was in vain.
Osman lost everything.
So, our castles are safe.
They are.
Salam Alaikum.
There is no God but Allah.
He is one. He owns everything.
And Muhammad is the messenger
of Allah.
Alaikum Salam.
You are obviously on the Allah's path.
Where are you coming from, old man?
Where are you going to?
I'm coming from Söğüt to
wherever our path leads to.
Söğüt, then.
I'm on my way to Kayı Tribe.
I know it.
All the beys are coming to the borders.
Osman Bey has been struggling for the
unity of the Turks.
True. The hope of the Turks
lie on the borders.
When we are united, neither the Byzantines
nor the Mongols can stop us.
The Muslim unity starts by
performing the salaat together.
Let's come together.
But let the bey be our imam.
Thank you.
My bey. The cart went
this way.
But ten horsemen went
The ones who departed...
are either İhvaz Bey or
the scouts.
But this isn't going to the Kayı Tribe.
They went to Kayı Tribe from here.
But these tracks...
it seems that they separated
İhvaz Bey from the caravan.
Cerkutay, Boran, Barkın.
Come with us.
The others will follow
the caravan.
As you order, my bey.
You shouldn't find the master, Osman.
I can't allow this.
Allahu Akbar.
Allah listens to those who praise him.
Allahu Akbar!
What will you do with Osman?
He is already done.
His beys turned their backs
on him.
Why are you still going to him?
Peace and mercy of Allah be on you.
Umur wanted to reach Osman too.
It wasn't his destiny.
Peace and mercy of Allah be on you.
The borders have many valiants.
But they have many traitors too.
İhvaz. İhvaz.
Yours is a life rotten
for a dream.
We don't rot, weasel.
Our roots are strong.
Our branches reach to the sky.
You are cheated.
I wish you could be my dog,
just like Barkın.
Come, Osman.
Come.
The traces go this way.
They must be close.
Take position.
Be cautious.
As you order, my bey.
Father.
Look, we are here.
My sheik?
My sheik is burning, Akça Dervish!
He is in flames.
My Allah, help us.
Kumral Abdal, run!
Run, Kumral Abdal!
My sheik is burning!
Do something1
Help him!
My sheik!
No!
My Allah!
Protect him!
My sheik is poisoned, Bala Hatun.
He is poisoned!
Father!
My Allah!
Father, no!
Please, please, please!
No!
My sheik!
İnhisar Castle
Osman Bey should come
on his own.
He should make his own
demands.
I'm not feeding his dogs.
Leave now.
I explained with words first.
But if you don't understand from words...
what do you want?
Just like this.
You will pay your taxes to
Osman Bey monthly.
Or we'll take your castle.
İrvaz Bey.
They killed them all.
All of them.
İrvaz Bey!
Osman.
Who did this!
İrvaz Bey!
İrvaz is dead.
You won't live long either.
You.
Osman.
Your light will surrender to my darkness.
Your darkness will be illuminated
by my sword.
End of episode 87.
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com